inspiredtaste.net 2018-01-28

# Inspired Taste Privacy and Terms

Everything you need to know about Inspired Taste policies, all in one place.

## Copyright and Photo and Recipe Permissions

As long Inspired Taste is credited for our work with a working link back to the original post, we will allow photos to be shared on other websites or blogs.

We rarely provide permission to do the same with full recipes or our articles. If you would like to republish one of our recipes on your website, please contact us first.

## Your Privacy

You are certainly not “data” to us-instead you are friends and people who make us very happy. Your privacy is no joke. When you comment on one of our blog posts, enter into one of our giveaways or sign up for newsletters you will be asked for an email address. The main purpose for this is so we know you’re a real person and not a spammer, and so we can personally reach out to you with answers to questions or if you’ve won one of our giveaways. That email address will be hidden once the comment or giveaway entry form is submitted.

Keep in mind however, if you write personal info like your full name or your email address in the body of your comment (or in the “Name” or “URL” field) that info can be viewed by anyone and all reading the comment section of that post. So keep it informal and just use your first name, keep your email address out of the comment itself and you will be fine. By contrast, your email address, as entered in the “E-mail” section of the comment form, will remain completely hidden from view.

## Inspired Taste’s Privacy Policy

This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog, website or app?**

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, mailing address, phone number or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter, respond to a survey, fill out a form Commenting or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

• To personalize user’s experience and to allow us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested.  
• To improve our website in order to better serve you.  
• To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests.  
• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.  
• To send periodic emails regarding your order or other products and services.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

We do use Malware Scanning.

We do not use an SSL certificate  
• We do not need an SSL because:  
we never ask for financial information such as credit card numbers.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart. They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to:  
• Keep track of advertisements.  
• Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled It won’t affect the users experience that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by [Google’s Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We have implemented the following:  
• Remarketing with Google AdSense  
• Google Display Network Impression Reporting  
• Demographics and Interests Reporting  
• DoubleClick Platform Integration

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

**Opting out:**  
Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at [here](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf).

According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:  
Users can visit our site anonymously  
Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  
Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

**Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:**  
• On our Privacy Policy Page  
Users are able to change their personal information:  
• By emailing us

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**  
We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**  
It’s also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13.

**Fair Information Practices**

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:  
We will notify the users via in site notification  
• Within 7 business days

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**  
• Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.  
• Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after the original transaction has occurred

To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:  
• NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses  
• Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way  
• Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters  
• Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.  
• Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly  
• Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

**If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can**  
• Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email.  
and we will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.

## Disclosure

This is a blog written and edited by Adam and Joanne Gallagher of Inspired Taste Inc. For questions about this blog, please contact  Adam Gallagher (adam@inspiredtaste.net). This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions or other forms of compensation. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post may not always be identified as paid or sponsored content. The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question. This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

Inspired Taste may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is valid from 27 January 2013.

### Amazon Affiliate Program

Inspired Taste is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to amazon.com

## Contact Us

**For Our Readers:**  We love to hear from you! Email us using inspiredtaste@gmail.com if you have a question, comment, photo of one of our recipes you have made (love these) or link you’d like to share.

**Advertising, Sponsored Posts and Giveaways:** We are happy to connect with you about advertising partnerships or discuss purchasing a sponsored post / giveaway. Please connect with us using inspiredtaste@gmail.com

Inspired Taste Inc.

2641 42nd Avenue SW

Seattle, WA 98116

**Page Last Updated on October  27, 2016**
